Guide to the Robert G. Dunbar Papers 1930-1986
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Research Files, 1936-1983; 2
  - Agricultural history and organizations, 3
    - Agricultural history - general materials - sociology of agriculture, organizations (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - American frontier - history and significance, several Frederick Jackson Turner pieces (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Farm Bureau (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Farmer and Politics - backgrounds of farmer's movements and organizations (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Farmer's organizations - National Farmers Organization (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Farmer's organizations - National Farmers Union (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Farmer's organizations - Non-Partisan League (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - History of the Grange - emphasis on Montana (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Holland Settlement, Montana - paper about its history (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Land Grant College System - includes transcriptions of R.R. Renne and R.G. Dunbar addresses at conference (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - M.L. Wilson - Remembrances of Edward Bell and Dr. Robert Dunbar (2 audio tapes)* (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Essays on sheep, cattle, sugar beets, poultry (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Fairway Farm Project by M.L. Wilson (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Farmer's organizations: Equity, Farmers Alliance, etc. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Montana Agricultural History - General topics: drought, crops, livestock, dairies (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Jack Taylor, Hobart E. Myrick, Mildred K. Stoltz and E.A. Willson interviews (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Kinsey Flats/Case-Wheeler Projects - interview with Elmer Starch, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Seed pea industry in Gallatin County by M.C. Parker and interview with John G. Parker (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Montana Agricultural History - Water resources (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Snow surveys - notes, correspondence, articles (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Williamsburg restored - articles, postcard (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - World history - set of journal articles including Napoleonic France, Europe and sundry topics (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Montana State University Development and Programs, 1948-1972; 3
  Files associated with Dr. Dunbar's career at Montana State University. These include his role as a member of the Curriculum and Instruction Committee including correspondence with numerous faculty members, Director for the Center for Inter-Cultural Affairs, founder of the International Studies Center, establishment of a Peace Corp program (Ecuador/Heifer) - includes extensive correspondence with Ray and Verena Borton of the Agricultural Development Council, Inc., the International Farm Youth Exchange program, and papers related to these programs.
  - Curriculum - Development: notes, background materials, correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum - Suggested course changes, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum - State and M.S.U. meeting, annual reports and correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum - dept. recommendations, surveys, meetings for five day week, 1951-1955 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum - development of education in the social sciences and humanities, 1951-1956 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - International Farm Youth Exchange - notes, papers, brochures, correspondence, etc. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - International Farm Youth Exchange - notes, papers, brochures, correspondence, etc. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - International Studies - correspondence, notes, articles, reports with emphasis on Latin America (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Peace Corp - Ecuador: reports by volunteers, maps, brochures, notes (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Peace Corp - Ecuador/Heifer: training evaluation, journals, pamphlets, notes (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Peace Corp - Correspondence, mainly from Ray and Verena Borton (Agricultural Development Council, Inc.) and some print materials and clippings, 1964-1972 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Peace Corp - Correspondence (cont.) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - World hunger - notes, journal articles, newspaper clippings and other background materials (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Agricultural Organizations, 1949-1980; 4
  Included are files for: 1. The Great Plains Foundation where he served as chairman of the committee for its original organization, papers include drafts of proposals, by-laws and correspondence relative to setting up the foundation; 2. The Montana Farmers Union for which he served on the Education Task Force. There is correspondence between Margaret Bucher, Director of Education about talks to the State School program and the Writer's Project, Ralph R. Cook regarding talks at picnics and camps across Montana and Leonard Kenfield as President of Montana Farmers Union. Also, he and Mildred K. Stoltz corresponded extensively about her history of the Montana Farmers Union. Research notes, publications (brochures, pamphlets, etc.) are interspersed in the files. Policy positions of the National Farmers Union and a set of Pioneer, the newsletter of the Educational Dept. complete the papers; 3. The Agricultural History Society where he was on the Editorial Board and later was President (1966-67), included are letters from Everett E. Edwards, Wayne D. Rasmussen, Vernon Carstensen and other editors, copies of reviews he wrote, missives on the hopes of a committee on World Agricultural History at the FAO and letters to authors with critiques and encouragement.
  - Great Plains Foundation - correspondence, notes, drafts of proposals, by-laws and other materials relative to establishing the foundation, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Montana Farmers Union - Correspondence (mainly Mildred K. Stoltz and Margaret Bucher) with enclosures, 1949-1957 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Montana Farmers Union - Correspondence, and research notes, 1958-1961 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Montana Farmers Union - Correspondence, convention hand-outs, service award program, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Montana Farmers Union - National Farmers Union policies, 1973-1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Montana Farmers Union - Set of Pioneer (Montana Farmers Union Educational Dept. Newsletter), 1979 March - 1980 October (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural History Society - correspondence including enclosures, 1947-1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Agricultural History Society - correspondence including enclosures, 1957-1958 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Bibliography, Correspondence, and Ephemera, 5
  The files consist of lists of books, articles and reviews authored by Robert G. Dunbar, copies of some of the articles (published items present in the library are individually cataloged), a file on the Dead Sea Scrolls, a set of personal and professional correspondence (with some enclosures) chronologically arranged, personal correspondence and loose papers and personal ephemera. Letters of recommendation from students and colleagues for educational institutions, organizations and government agencies are restricted. **
  - Publication lists, 1937-1986 and some copies of published articles (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls research papers (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Research on vaccination history in France and miscellaneous correspondence (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Assorted loose papers and correspondence (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Assorted brochures, pamphlets and other ephemera (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Mildred C. Robbins to Robert Dunbar, 1927-1929 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - personal and professional, 1947-1978 (Box 18, Folder 2-6)
  - Letters of recommendation - Restricted**, 1953-1962 (Box 18, Folder 7)